开萝尔:我会永远记住这场冬日的舞会,
Carol: It's just that I'd always remember this winter formal dance,
这将是我一生中最美好的一个夜晚.
best night in my entire life.
鲍比:就算这件礼服只值五十美元,我也不会有所介意.
Bobby: You know I don't even mind if it costs fifty bucks for the monkey suit.
开萝尔:鲍比,你看上去真帅.
Carol: You look so handsome Bobby.
鲍比:站在你旁边的感觉真好
Bobby: I feel good looking next to you.
开萝尔:什么?
Carol: Pardon me?
鲍比:我是说你是如此美艳,
Bobby: Well, I...I mean I must be good looking we go around totally had
站在你旁边我也沾光了.
looking is you.
开萝尔:哦?
Carol: Oh?
鲍比:我很喜欢你这套快要掉下来的礼服,看上去很性感.
Bobby: I sure like your dress looking sexily falloff.
鲍比:真高心你能懂我的心
Bobby: I am sure glad you understand me.
开萝尔:是的,你也明白我的心
Carol: Well, you understand me.
鲍比:当然.
Bobby: I do?
开萝尔:我在想什么呀?
Carol: What am I thinking?
迈克:我想我们创造了新的记录.
Mike: I believe we have a record here?
开萝尔:迈克,什么意思呀?
Carol: Mike?
迈克:你看你的肩膀都是猩红的,当然是除了鲍比那白色的手印外.
Mike: Really, even your shoulder is blushing in the air.Oh, except for Bobby's left
white fingerprint, of course
开萝尔:麦克·西沃,你这个无情的,野蛮的,低级粗俗的家伙.
Carol: Mike Seaver, you are the drowsiest, rudest, most insensitive guy.
迈克:好了,好了,头都被你搞大了.
Mike: Please, Carol, please.I get a big head.
开萝尔:我可不想让你这个傻大哥来破坏这美好的夜晚.
Carol: I am not going to let my stupid brother ruin this perfect evening.
鲍比:对了,有件事要对你讲.
Bobby: Good, 'cause I had something that I want to say.
开萝尔:就这样不说话挺好的.
Carol: Little conversation could be inhered.
鲍比:不,不,这话我一定得跟你讲.
Bobby: No, no, I mean not talking with words.
开萝尔:哦?
Carol: Oh?
鲍比:听我讲,我发现一个惊人的事.
Bobby: You see, I got a sort of surprise.
开萝尔:什么?
Carol: what?
鲍比:我一直在想.
Bobby: I've been thinking...
开萝尔:真的吗?
Carol: Really?
鲍比:不,这并非什么惊人的事,你明白我是爱你的.
Bobby: No, that's not a surprise.You see, I love you.
开萝尔:哇,我也爱你.
Carol: Wow, Well, I love you too.
鲍比:我们俩已经都说出来了.
Bobby: We said it, Both said it.
开萝尔:哦,是的,我们都说出来了.
Carol: Oh, We sure did.
鲍比:开萝尔,做我的妻子吧!嫁给我好吗?
Bobby: Carol, would you be my wife, would you marry me?
开萝尔:结婚?
Carol: Marry?
鲍比:我不是说现在,是到明年我们毕业后,
Bobby: I don't mean it right now, I mean next year after we graduate,
你知道要是我们不……
you see, if we don't... then you know...
开萝尔:结婚?
Carol: Marry?
鲍比:我是说我在一个学校拿足球奖学金而你在另一个学校拿助学奖学金.
Bobby: I mean to get the football scholarship at one place;
you'll get your real scholarship at some place else.
开萝尔:结婚?
Carol: Marry?
鲍比:我这辈子要是能和你在一起的话将会非常幸福.
Bobby: It could secure 'cause it's been the best even in my entire life.
开萝尔:是的.
Carol: Yes.
鲍比:什么是的?
Bobby: Yes?What?
开萝尔:是的,我愿意做你的妻子.
Carol: Yes, will be your wife.
杰森:我的剃须镜怎么都被扔到花园里了.
Jason: Dropping the shaving mirror in the bushes.
麦琪:你怎么把头伸到窗外去刮胡子呢?
Maggie: Why are you shaving hanging out of the window?
杰森:我一点也听不到鲍比和开萝尔在门廊那里的说话声,
Jason: I just try to see what Carol and Bobby are doing since I cannot
所以我就把头伸到窗外去听,
hear anything.They are on the porch...
他们已经谈了二十八分十七秒了.
They have been on there for 28 minutes and 17 seconds.
麦琪:我真想用同样的时间好好说说你有多蠢,
Maggie: Well I'd like to spend at least the same long time to say that
但是我得先去上厕所一趟.
how silly you are, but I have to go to the bathroom.
杰森:哦,什么?
Jason: Oh, silly?Am I?
说我愚蠢?我为我那年轻的女儿担忧难道也算愚蠢?
I am just silly to be worried about your teenager daughter,
和她第一个男朋友出去约会,
who's out with her very first dated boyfriend and who was wearing a dress
居然让她穿成那样,要是我事先知道绝对不会让她这样穿的.
that I certainly would never approve of if I could be said to her.
好吧!老老实实地告诉我难道这也叫愚蠢?
Is that silly?Tell me, That's great, give me an understandable answer , Ok?
麦琪:杰森,开萝尔可是花了很多心思在那礼服上了.
Maggie: Carol had a heart set on that dress, Jason.
杰森:是啊!要是领口再低点,恐怕是真的能看到她的心了.
Jason: Even if her dress has been cut in lorry be able to see her heart.
开萝尔:妈妈,爸爸.
Carol: Mom, dad.
麦琪:你在干什么?
Maggie: What are you doing?
杰森:我们不能让开萝尔知道我们在等她.
Jason: We wouldn't let Carol think we 've waited up for.
麦琪:我们?
Maggie: We?
杰森:是的,难道你睡着了?进来吧!宝贝.
Jason: Well, you are not awake, aren't you?You sweet heart, honey.
开萝尔:嘿!我只想让你们知道我回来了.
Carol: Hi, just want to let you know that I got home, ok?
杰森:这会才回来?
Jason: Just now?
麦琪:你的第一次社交舞会怎么?
Maggie: How was your first formal?
开萝尔:哦,太棒了!人人都很喜欢我的礼服.
Carol: Oh, wonderful, everybody loves my dress,
杰森:看上去挺好的.
Jason: Not bad.
开萝尔:爸爸妈妈,你们觉得是不是该请鲍比的父母来我们家吃晚饭?
Carol: Mon man dad, don't you think it's about time that we had Bobby's parents
over for dinner
麦琪:当然,随时可以.
Maggie: Of course, anytime.
开萝尔:太棒了!我知道你们会同意的,
Carol: Great, I knew you would say that.
我已经让鲍比下星期五带父母来我们家,晚安.
I had bobby invite them for next Friday.Good night!
开萝尔:下星期五?等等.
Carol: Next Friday?Hold on.
开萝尔:什么?
Carol: What?
杰森:什么事怎么这么急?
Jason: What's the hurry?
开萝尔:没有呀!你们有什么问题吗?
Carol: No hurry.Is there a problem?
杰森和麦琪:不,不
Jason and Maggie: No, no.
开萝尔:
Carol: Great, Oh, here dad, someone left your shaving mirror in the bushes.
杰森:本真是欠揍!
Jason: The dern Ben.
同学:这简直令人难以置信,居然会发生这样的事!
Classmate: Absolutely it's the most fabulous thing that had ever happened.
同学:这钻石是真的吗?
Classmate: Is it a real diamond?
开萝尔:当然,你看这么小就知道是真的了.
Carol: Well, of course it is real.That's why so small.
同学:开萝尔·西沃已经订婚了.
Classmate: Well, Carol Seaver is engaged.
开萝尔:小声点,这可是绝密的,现在除了你们十二个人外加鲍比和我,就没人知道这事了.
Carol: Hush, now that's the top secret. No body knows this except Bob and me
and 12 of you
迈克:我刚刚听到一个天大的谣言,现在学校里面的人都在谣传你和鲍比已经订婚了.
Mike: I've just heard the dopiest rumor of my entire life;
somebody is exactly spreading all around school that you and Bobby are,
get this, engaged.
迈克:你不是当真的吧?你是不是开玩笑?开萝尔,这真是令人难以置信!好了,老实说吧,这到底怎么回事?
Mike: You mean it is true?What are you kidding?Carol, I can't believe it
Now, come on, you are shocking me, right
开萝尔:再见,迈克.
Carol: Good bye, Mike.
迈克:开萝尔,等会,
Mike: Wait a minute, Carol, You were serious?
你不会当真吧?鲍比只是你第一个约会的男生呀!
He, look, come on, Bobby is the first guy you ever went on with.
开萝尔:那有怎么样?
Carol: So ?
迈克:那有怎么样?换成我的话,我肯定不会跟我的第一个约会的女孩结婚.你知道我的意思吗?比如说你最喜欢吃的辣狗吧,如果让你连着两个月吃,你肯定会吃腻的,对吗?
Mike: So, look, I am just saying that.Look, I wouldn't go often to marry
the first guy that I ever dated?You know what I mean.Look, I am
just saying chile dogs, chile dogs would be the first food that you ever ate
Ok?Say you ate dose day after day after days.You know?A couple of
months probably puke your guts out.Right
开萝尔:你真是令人讨厌!
Carol: You are disgusting.
迈克:好了,不讲辣狗了,说说馅饼吧
Mike: All right, forget Chile dogs, let's take pizza.
开萝尔:别讲了,好吗?我要去上课了!另外求你在星期五之前别让爸妈知道这件事.
Carol: Let's not, ok?I've got to take classes, ok?Just don't tell mom and
dad about these people before I do on Friday night ok
迈克:开萝尔,你是不是疯了?他们知道了肯定会气炸的,妈妈肯定会暴跳如雷,爸爸肯定会怒不可遏.我敢保证到时他们肯定会气的大喊大叫的.
Mike: Carol, you are crazy.They are going freak... Mom is going to do this
until she is airborne, and dad's eyes are just going to bug out.I wouldn't
surprised, if they shout out across the room
开萝尔:好了,一开始他们可能会这样,但只要他们听了我们合情合理的理由,到时就会同意我和鲍比在一起了.
Carol: Ok, they maybe react as that way first and then once it does settles, they'll hear our eer suitable reasons.I now realize just how committed Bobby and I are.
迈克:不,他们会觉得你已经不再听话了.
Mike: No, they all realize you should be committed.
开萝尔:本,待会鲍比的父母要来做客,
Carol: Ben, soon Bobby's parents are coming over,
你到时可得乖乖听话呀!
I want you on company behavior tonight.
本:好的!好的!好的!
Ben: Yeah, Yeah, Yeah.
开萝尔:如果你老是这样无礼的喧闹,就先请你离开这房子.
Carol: If you are to make a rude noise, leave the room first.
本:怎么无礼的喧闹了?
Ben: How rude?
开萝尔:马上给我走开.
Carol: Just leave.
杰森:宝贝,你还想把这些沙发靠垫整理几遍?
Jason: Honey, how many times you've got straight those pillows?
开萝尔:我只是希望每样东西都能摆好.
Carol: I just want every thing to be perfect.
本:好吧!离开就离开!
Ben: Oops, got to leave the room.
杰森:我在想她是从哪里弄来这么多垫子的.
Jason: I wonder where she gets it.
开萝尔:等等,妈妈,这些银餐具放在这里太不妥了.
Carol: Wait, mom.Using our good silver is a mistake.
麦琪:我以为你要让他们留下印象的.
Maggie: But I think you want to impress them.
开萝尔:我是这么想的,但是这些银餐具会吓到他们的.
Carol: Yeah, but our silver could intimidate them.
杰森:哦,好吧!到时我们就用手来吃饭吧!
Jason: Ah.., well, we just eat with our hands and rip the food apart.
鲍比:嘿,西沃太太,西沃医生,开萝尔,你们晚上好.
Bobby: Hi, Mrs.Seaver, Hi, Doctor Seaver.Carol.Good evening.
开萝尔:妈妈,爸爸,这是鲍比的父母.
Carol: Mom, Dad... these are Bobby's parents
鲍比:哦,是的,这是我父母.
Bobby: oh, yeah.
凯蒂:我是凯蒂.
Kitty: I'm kitty.
麦琪:我是麦琪.
Maggie: I'm Maggie,
杰森:我是杰森.
Jason: I am Jason,
罗伯特:我是罗伯特.
Robert: I am Robert.
麦琪:站着干什么?快进来吧!
Maggie: Well, won't you come in?
罗伯特:我们已经进来了.
Robert: We are in.
麦琪:好吧,为何不再进来一点?
Maggie: Well, won't you come in further?
开萝尔:给你们拿四杯冰茶怎么样?
Carol: 4 Ice Teas and you whole?
凯蒂:谢谢,开萝尔.
Kitty: Thank you.Carol.
鲍比:开萝尔,一切就如同你说的那样,
Bobby: Oh, Carol, It's going just as you said.
他们已经开始谈笑风生了,
They started to talk and smile and everything.And my dad, my dad ...
你妈还说她喜欢凯瑟琳和南茜,还有我爸……
you mom says she likes Catharine and Nancy.
开萝尔:我们不要等到吃完饭以后了,现在就去告诉他们.
Carol: Let's not wait till after dinners to tell them.Let's tell them now.
鲍比:好的,不过记得让我先说.
Bobby: Ok, remember, let me talk first.
开萝尔:鲍比,还是让我说吧.
Carol: I'll talk, Bobby.
开萝尔:大家注意了,我们有件事要向你们宣布.
Carol: Ok, everyday, We have an announcement.
迈克:等等,我可不想错过这一刻.
Mike: Wait a minute.I don't want to miss this.
麦琪:凯蒂,罗伯特,这是我的大儿子.
Maggie: Kitty, Robert, This is my oldest son,
迈克:妈妈,这小事就免谈了.开萝尔,快讲呀!
Mike: Mom, That's not important.Go ahead, Carol.
本:是怎么一回事呀?
Ben: What's it all about?
罗伯特:快讲啊!.
Robert: Yes.
本:是不是要宣布吃饭了?
Ben: Is it going for the dinner?
开萝尔:首先我得告诉大家我并没有怀孕.
Carol: First of all, I want you all to know that I am not pregnant.
麦琪:什么?
Maggie: What?
杰森:开萝尔?
Jason: Carol?
罗伯特:好好解释一下!
Robert: Somebody had better explain this.
杰森:开萝尔,到底是怎么一回事?
Jason: Carol, what is it?
开萝尔:好吧,是这样的.
Carol: Ok, here goes.
等到明年高中毕业选择了大学后,
Next year a week after graduation after Bobby and I both chose our colleges.
我们想举行婚礼.他们的反应比我想象的要好很多.
Bobby and I are getting married.They are taking it far better than I thought.
麦琪:开萝尔,你们可不能结婚!
Maggie: Carol, you are not getting married.
罗伯特:这是我一生中见过的最愚蠢的事!
Robert: Stupid thing in my life...
(大家开始争吵)
(They are quarreling )
开萝尔:我并不觉得这事有什么不好.
Carol: This is good, every body.Great!
罗伯特而:这个家庭怎么这样!
Robert: What a family it is!
迈克:先听听他们怎么讲的,再找个合适的时机说服他们
Mike: Listen to everyone and how to take advantage and instruct parents.
本:快告诉我.
Ben: Tell me...
杰森:这不会起任何作用的.
Jason: This doesn't make any sense.
迈克:妈妈,爸爸.
Mike: Mom and dad.
杰森:迈克,你现在给我闭嘴!
Jason: Not now.Mike.
迈克:我只是想问你能不能让我和波纳一起出去玩会.
Mike: I was just wondering if I can go with Boner to this most grestling joy.
麦琪:好的.
Maggie: Fine.
迈克:谢谢.
Mike: Thank you.
本:哇!
Ben: Well!
罗伯特:说话呀!你到底在想什么呀?
Robert: ...what did you think?
鲍比:爸爸,我知道,她能……
Bobby: I know, papa, she can...
罗伯特:快回答我!
Robert: I wait for an answer,
本:妈妈,爸爸.
Ben: Mom and Dad.
麦琪:本,现在给我闭嘴!
Maggie: Not now, Ben
本:我想问一下现在能不能吃点点心.
Ben: I was just to ask if I can eat everybody's dessert.
杰森:当然不行.
Jason: Absolutely not.
本:该死.
Ben: knot.
杰森:好了,各位!
Jason: Ok, everybody!!!Now discussion is usually much more productive
我想我们要是能更平静和理性地讨论,效果也许会更好.
if we can be calm and rational.
凯蒂:是的.
Kitty: Yes.
开萝尔:谢谢,爸爸.
Carol: Thank you, Dad.
开萝尔:现在你们准备好听听解释了吗?
Carol: Now, are you all ready to hear our reason?
罗伯特:我才不要听什么解释.
Robert: I don't really want to hear kaka.
麦琪:我们现在怎么能理智起来呢?
Maggie: How could you expect us to be common rational?
凯蒂:罗伯特,你踩到我脚了.
Kitty: Robert, you are standing on my foot.
杰森:我们是不是应该让孩子们说完呢?开萝尔,
Jason: We need to let our children give them out.All right?
鲍比,真是抱歉!
Carol and Bobby, We are sorry.
罗伯特:抱歉?什么?
Robert: Sorry?What?
麦琪:孩子们,你俩去厨房待着,大人们要谈谈.
Maggie: Kids, Wait in the kitchen, the grown-up need to talk.
开萝尔:可是你还没听我们解释……
Carol: But you have to hear ......
麦琪:开萝尔?
Maggie: Carol?
开萝尔:那我们待会再谈.
Carol: We'll talk later.
麦琪:杰森,刚才孩子们进来跟我们宣布这件蠢事,
Maggie: Jason, It's kids walking here and making this crazy announcement,
而你还向他们道歉,这真是愚蠢极了.
that you apologize to them, that's so wrong.
罗伯特:哇,讲的对极了!
Robert: Wow, That's right.
麦琪:谢谢,罗伯特,你可真是个明辨是非的人呀!
Maggie: Thanks, Robert, you are a sensible man.
凯蒂:罗伯特,你可错了.
Kitty: Robert, you are wrong.
罗伯特:哇,我们可和你们不同,
Robert: Wo, we are not like these people we don't have a dominating woman
在我们家可是男人作主.
in our family.
麦琪:你说什么?
Maggie: Excuse me?
罗伯特:我是说开萝尔可真是杰森的好女儿呀!
Robert: That's to say she was a daughter of Jason.
杰森:等等,我们都先喘口气.
Jason: Wait, let's all just catch a breath here.
麦琪:开萝尔跟谁学的,这是什么意思啊?
Maggie: Well, our daughter gets a what?
罗伯特:她把鲍比弄得团团转,就像现在杰森被你弄得团团转一样!
Robert: She's leading Bobby Robert's nose hairs.Just like you do Jason here.
杰森:什么?
Jason: What?
鲍比:我是说我们一起想了这个计划,但现在这计划让他们几乎要疯了.
Bobby: I mean you know the part of our plan,
开萝尔,
they all just get so mad and let it out.I don't know, Carol.
现在我也不知道怎么办?我本以为这计划会成功的.
I think it's working too good.
开萝尔:是的,我想我爸正在试图让他们平静下来,
Carol: Yes, my dad is trying to do.
然后一起好好交谈一下.
I am sure he has now got them all calm down and ready to talk.
罗伯特:好了,你们俩现在待这里,
Robert: Well, fine then.
我们俩去厨房.
You stay where you are and we'll go and stay in kitchen.
鲍比:好了,开萝尔,我想会没事的.
Bobby: Oh, Carol, I think it will be ok.
开萝尔:你对我真好.
Carol: You are so sweet.
鲍比:你是不是想到好办法了?
Bobby: You think something.
开萝尔:嘿!
Carol: Hi.
杰森:你和鲍比,现在给我到别的地方去.
Jason: You and Bobby have to go.Somewhere else.
开萝尔:哪里?
Carol: Where?
罗伯特:我有个建议.
Robert: I got the suggestions.
杰森:我们现在到外面冷静一下吧
Jason: Just go outside, cool off.
鲍比:这里一点也不热啊.
Bobby: It's not so hot here?
开萝尔:来吧,鲍比.
Carol: Come on, Bobby
鲍比:好的,亲爱的.
Bobby: ok, honey.
罗伯特:你太傻了,你在听我讲话吗?她让你变得太傻了!
Robert: You are wept.You hear me?She's getting you wept.
杰森:晚上真美!
Jason: What a night!
罗伯特:这些孩子在搞什么呀?
Robert: What is with these kids?
罗伯特:他们手拉着手,
Robert: They hold hands.
注视着对方,
Make googoo eyes in each other,
还以为结了婚就会更浪漫!
they think they are in love or take a lot more than love that put up
你在干什么?
marriage.How are you doing?
杰森:我在烤鸭子.
Jason: I am basting the roast.
罗伯特:麦琪让你来烤鸭子?你真是听话呀!
Robert: She's got you doing the cooking?No fancy belly.
连我的孩子也不如你这么乖.
You are bigger than my kids.
杰森:我这么聪明的女儿居然会和这样的蠢事绞在一起,
Jason: I am expanding some nervous energy trying to figure out how my
我真是死活也想不通呀!
smart daughter could come up with something so stupid.
罗伯特:你说这全是我孩子的错了?
Robert: So you sense my kid's faults?
杰森:当然是他的错了.但现在责备也于事无补了,
Jason: Of course, it is his fault.But the blame is not the issue here.
要想今晚能顺利解决这件事,我想我们还得要好好听听孩子们怎么讲的.
We have to do with it rationally if you want to make headway tonight.
罗伯特:是的,他们要是还敢继续交往,
Robert: Right.How about if they ever see each other again,
我发誓将他们的腿折断.
we break their legs?
杰森:好了,罗伯特,
Jason: Come on, Robert, now what if Kitty's father has frightened you,
要是凯蒂的父亲这样威胁你,你会怎样?
what would you have done?
罗伯特:你就别管我怎么做!对鲍比来讲就不同了,
Robert: What I did don't matter.Bobby is different.
要是有了足球奖学金,
With this football scholarship ...
他将会是我们家的第一个大学生.足球是我教他的,
he is going to be the first one in our family ever to go to college.
每天一做完功课,我就督促他训练,
I taught him the game.Everyday after work... I looked in.
除了踢球,
When we started, what's much bigger than the football.
其他方面他都不怎么会.老实说,
look, I think Carol is a real good kid I do.
我觉得开萝尔是个好孩子,可是她和鲍比都不在这里,
But she and Bobby has been out here.They don't know.
他们并不知道.
And Bobby should don't need the person to be married before he gets to
鲍比要想成为国脚,现在就是不能有结婚打算.
take the shot.
杰森:你对鲍比大声呵斥是不会有很大作用的,
Jason: and don't you think Bobby would respond a lot better to what you
还是好好和他谈谈你的心里话.
said than to yelling.
罗伯特:是啊,为什么你不去跟他们说?
Robert: Yeah, you would, so will you tell them?
麦琪:你看,鲍比和开萝尔是完全不同的人,他俩的追求不同.我想开萝尔真应该放弃鲍比,我想她有更好的选择.
Maggie: Look, Kitty.Bobby and Carol are so different.They want different things.I really think Carol give up, have a chance, she can really do the whole of the fatic.
凯蒂:更好的?你是说开萝尔有更好的选择?
Kitty: fatic... you are going to say fatic.
麦琪:我不是这个意思,我是说……
Maggie: But I don't mean that?I meant...
凯蒂:聪慧?
Kitty: Smarter?
麦琪:是的,你明白的.
Maggie: Yeah, you know.
凯蒂::这样讲对鲍比太不公平了,要知道没有健全的身体,脑子再灵光又有什么用呐?
Kitty: I don't think that's very fair.I mean as arkens go, then brains are not so important,
麦琪:你说得对,凯蒂,真是抱歉!
Maggie: You are right, Kitty, I am very sorry.
杰森:好了,大家都说说自己的看法吧,
Jason: All right, is everybody ready to discuss this situation with reason
不过不要太激动呀!
and self-possession?
罗伯特:杰森,我们肯定会的.
Robert: 'Cause we certainly are, right Jason.
凯蒂:罗伯特,你喝酒了?
Kitty: Robert, Have you been drinking?
罗伯特:没有呀!我俩一直在烤鸭子.
Robert: No, we've been basting the roast.
杰森:开萝尔,鲍比,现在讲讲你们的解释吧!
Jason: Carol and Bobby, we are ready to hear your reasons now.
罗伯特:我们很想听听.
Robert: Certainly we are.
开萝尔:首先,
Carol: Point 1.by marrying before first-year college,
进大学就结婚的话,我们就可以在学校附近租个房子住在一起,
we'll be able to take a small apartment off campus together.
这样就可以为双方父母节省一笔不菲的开销.
And therefore save our wonderful parents a great deal of money.
麦琪:开萝尔,节省开销不是结婚的理由,但我肯定你爸爸以前也是这么想过的.
Maggie: Carol, a financial saving like that is not a reason to get married.I
am sure being the same for your father
开萝尔:好吧,另外……
Carol: Ok, all right.
鲍比:嘿,这些主意都是开萝尔想到的.
Bobby: Hi, we've got a lot of more reasons Carol folk up.
开萝尔:好吧,那就讲第二点,你们可能认为我们现在太年轻了,不过我想你们在我们这样的年纪的时候不是就已经结婚了.
Carol: Right, ok, point 2, you probably think we are too young to finish it.but
I'd like to point out that we are about the same age that all of
you were when you get married
杰森:开萝尔,
Jason: Carol, our situation is not relevant to yours.
那时的情况不同,
If you've got to make your case based on something that pertaining only
你只能说些和你俩有关的理由.
to you and Bobby.
开萝尔:可是爸爸,我……
Carol: But dad, I ...
罗伯特:说得太好了
Robert: Nice move.
开萝尔:你不是说会好好听我们讲的吗?
Carol: You swear you are going to listen to us.
罗伯特:他是在听呀,你看看!
Robert: He is listening.Look at him.
杰森:我是在听呀.
Jason: I am listening.
开萝尔:所有的解释都没用,看来你们还只是把我们看成小孩.
Carol: So all reasons don't really matter.You were just treating us children.
杰森:孩子,我用的是人
Jason: Kids, I mean people,
开萝尔:你真狡猾!
Carol: It stinks.
鲍比:你们要是不听我们的,我们也就不听你们的.
Bobby: If you cannot listen to us.Then I cannot listen to you either.
凯蒂:但是你什么也没有说呀?鲍比.
Kitty: But you haven't said anything, Bobby.
鲍比:开萝尔说的就代表我说的.
Bobby: That's because Carol is speaking for two.
罗伯特:那她真的怀孕了.
Robert: So she is pregnant.
开萝尔:不,我没有
Carol: No, I am not.
罗伯特:鲍比,听着,起码要是你还想住在我那,现在你就得听我的.
Robert: Listen, bobby, bottom line.If you are on to still live under my roof
You've got to do what I say
鲍比:也许我还是最好另外找地方住.
Bobby: Maybe I had better find another roof to live under.
开萝尔:你们怎么这么不讲道理!
Carol: How could you be so... so Berrintal.
凯蒂:看来今晚大家都过得很开心呀!
Kitty: Well, we had a lovely evening.
开萝尔:鲍比!
Carol: Bobby.
鲍比:开萝尔!
Bobby: Carol.
开萝尔:你来这里干什么?
Carol: What are you doing here?
鲍比:开萝尔,今晚我算是重新认清了自己,你知道我是一个不善言词的人……
Bobby: Carol, I was born the second myself tonight.I am not a man who
is like, good with some
开萝尔:言词?
Carol: Words?
鲍比:是的.
Bobby: Right.
鲍比:我只是个……
Bobby: I am a man who is of...
开萝尔:那马上行动吧!
Carol: Action.
鲍比:开萝尔,你看这就是我们心灵相通的原因,原来你也决定……
Bobby: Exactly, you see, Carol, that's why we have been long lasting because you can make.You know...
开萝尔:你快说完啊?
Carol: Complete your thoughts?
鲍比:你真是我的心肝!好了,今晚我俩就私奔吧!
Bobby: Sometimes you can suck off.Ok, here it is.You and me, we elope tonight.
开萝尔:现在?
Carol: Now?
鲍比:在父母采取行动之前,我们必须马上私奔.
Bobby: We had to elope before parents can make anything up.
开萝尔:鲍比,我不知道
Carol: Bobby, I don't know.
鲍比:难道你能想到我们不该结婚的理由?
Bobby: But you can come up with some reasons that we shouldn't get married?
开萝尔:不是,但……
Carol: No, but...
鲍比:那就行了.
Bobby: Ok, right.
开萝尔:但是必须今晚吗?
Carol: But, tonight?
鲍比:好了,我们彼此都很相配,
Bobby: Ok, you're right for each other, I am right for each other,
我才不管何时何地举行婚礼,你难道不是吗
it doesn't matter when and where to get married, doesn't it?.
开萝尔:是的,但……
Carol: No, but...
鲍比:开萝尔,我爱你.
Bobby: Carol, I love you.
开萝尔:是的,我也爱你.
Carol: Well, I love you too.
鲍比:那么现在我们该做什么?是不是该马上……
Bobby: So, what will we be going to do about it?It's time for an...
开萝尔:那马上行动吧!
Carol: Action.
鲍比:我的车停在街上了.
Bobby: My car is parked in the street.
开萝尔:太棒了!我爱你.
Carol: Oh, great.oh, I love you.
鲍比:我也爱你.
Bobby: I love you.
鲍比:明天我吻的人就是罗伯特太太了!
Bobby: Just thinking.By this time tomorrow, be kissing a Mrs.Robert.
开萝尔:你妈妈也要一起去?
Carol: Your mother is coming with us?
鲍比:不是,我是说你
Bobby: There'll be you.
开萝尔:但我不想改姓.
Carol: Oh, but I don't want to change my name.
鲍比:哦?
Bobby: Oh?
开萝尔:我以为你知道的.
Carol: I thought you knew that.
鲍比:不,这不要紧,至少我爱你.
Bobby: No, I ... it doesn't matter.I love you.
开萝尔:哦,我也爱你.
Carol: Oh, I love you.
开萝尔:你知道吗?我现在真的很盼望.
Carol: You know I am really looking forward to?
鲍比:是的,我也一样.
Bobby: Yeah, me too.
开萝尔:不,明年我们该在波士顿租个小公寓
Carol: No, next year, we'll get our little apartment in Boston.
鲍比:啊,哪里?
Bobby: Yeah, where?
开萝尔:波士顿,哈佛就在那里.
Carol: Boston, where Harvord is.
鲍比:哦,你想去哈佛?
Bobby: Oh, you want to go to Harvord?
开萝尔:进哈佛一直是我的梦想.
Carol: It's always been my dream.
鲍比:得了,我想我们应该去更好的学校.
Bobby: Well, I thought we can go to a good school.
开萝尔:你认为哈佛不是一所好学校?
Carol: You don't think Harvord is a good school?
鲍比:是的,哈佛的足球不行,你可以在足球排名前十的学校里选,比如俄亥俄,密歇根,伊里诺斯等等
Bobby: No, not in football.You can get all big 10 schools, Ohio state, Michigan, Illinois and ..
开萝尔:什么?
Carol: What?
鲍比:我还以为你了解这些学校,足球是我的梦想.
Bobby: Yeah, I thought you knew that, that is my dream.
开萝尔:但是哈佛是我的梦想呀!这不要紧的,至少我爱你
Carol: But Hardvord is mine.Well, it doesn't matter.I love you.
鲍比:你冷吗?
Bobby: Are you cold?
开萝尔:是的.
Carol: Yeah.
鲍比:我爱你.
Bobby: I love you.
开萝尔:我也爱你.
Carol: I love you.
鲍比:我们都决定了.
Bobby: Oh, we made it.
开萝尔:当然是的
Carol: We sure did.
开萝尔:以后明天都能和你一起吃早饭真是太好了.
Carol: How all will it be great to have breakfast together every day?
鲍比:是的,还有晚饭.我想到时足球训练后,我会马上赶回家帮你做家务.
Bobby: Yeah, and dinner too.I can see that I must rush home from the
football practice, not expecting you to do the all cook, no serf
开萝尔:这是幸福呀!
Carol: So sweet.
鲍比:我们可以订一些汉堡,中国菜以及辣狗.
Bobby: We can order out burgers, Chinese food and chile dogs.
开萝尔:辣狗?
Carol: Chile dogs?
鲍比:是的,辣狗人人都喜欢的.我爱你!怎么了?开萝尔.
Bobby: Yes, Everybody can want.I love you.Carol, are you ok?
开萝尔:我在想……
Carol: I am thinking
鲍比:想什么呢?
Bobby: About What?
开萝尔:辣狗.
Carol: Chile dogs
鲍比:你想吃些别的吧!你决定好了,披萨怎么样?
Bobby: You want something else, You got it.How is it about pizza?
开萝尔:也许我们真的做错了.
Carol: Maybe we are not doing the right thing.
鲍比:我们都说好了呀!
Bobby: We talk everything over.
开萝尔:是的.
Carol: Yes.
鲍比:我想你求婚,你也接受了,对吧?
Bobby: I propose, you accept it, Right?
开萝尔:是的.
Carol: Yes.
鲍比:我们只是将婚期略微提前了一些.
Bobby: We're also going to push the wedding date up a measly year.
开萝尔:我自己还是不确定.
Carol: I am not so sure about that.
鲍比:你不是老说我们是天生的一对吗?
Bobby: You always say we are perfect for each other.
开萝尔:我知道,也许我们应该把婚期延迟一点,我们还是明年结婚吧!
Carol: I know, maybe we should just delay our planning.Next year we will get married...
鲍比:你在说什么啊?什么叫婚期延迟一年举行?
Bobby: What are you talking about?What is it going to change in a year?
开萝尔:可是,我不能……
Carol: Well, I can't ...
鲍比:说说你改变主意的理由.
Bobby: Why are you going to change?
开萝尔:鲍比,我……
Carol: Bobby...I..
鲍比:你根本没什么理由可讲的.
Bobby: One thing is going to be different.
开萝尔:我不能……
Carol: I can't ...
鲍比:要是你认为一年后结婚是个好主意,
Bobby: So if it's good idea to get married a year from now,
那么今晚马上结婚也是一个好主意,
then it's also a good idea to get married tonight.
否则那就是我们考虑的这件事从一开始就是错的.
If it is, then the whole thing is a mistake.
开萝尔:是的,还有很多事我没想到.
Carol: There's so much I didn't think about.
鲍比:这样啊?
Bobby: Yeah.
开萝尔:你我就不要再争下去了.
Carol: You're not arguing with me.
鲍比:好好,不争了.
Bobby: I...I can't.
开萝尔:好吧,我想应该把这还给你,这应该很贵的.
Carol: Yeah.Well, I should return this.Sure, it was expensive.
鲍比:谢谢!
Bobby: Thanks.
开萝尔:那么……
Carol: So...
鲍比:那么……
Bobby: So...
鲍比:有机会我们再见.
Bobby: I see you around sometime.
开萝尔:嘿,别忘了你的夹克.
Carol: Yeah, Your jacket?
鲍比:送给你吧.
Bobby: No, You keep it.
迈克:谢谢你,波纳,慢点开车!哦!开萝尔,你真是吓我一跳,不过以后你也要小心一点
Mike: Aha, thanks a lot, Boner.Drive safely.Oh, Carol, I.., you scared me.But then again you are always scary.
开萝尔:迈克.
迈克:好了,开萝尔!,好了!
00:23:16,800
Carol: Mike. Mike: It's ok, Carol, it's ok.